Shubham Gulati

Senior Software Engineer • Certified Cloud Architect • 7 Years Experience • B.Tech & M.Tech

Waterloo, ON · linkedin.com/in/iamshgulati · shubhamgulati.com

PROFILE

Shubham is an award-winning Senior Software Engineer with 7 years of exceptional IT experience at industry leading U.S. and Canadian professional services firms. He has a Masters degree in Computer Science & Engineering and is certified in AWS. His core competencies include cloud-native web application development using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2022-2022

- Lead a team of junior developers that enhanced the accuracy of a reporting application by 30%.
- Streamlined development lifecycle by enforcing coding best practices and improved reliability of the system.
- Reduced the risk of security incidents by designing a framework to fetch configuration secrets from HashiCorp Vault.

Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2019-2022

- Developed the client's support portal which is a one stop shop for all the support related needs for business users.
- Reduced technical debt for a major client project by developing a common foundation for microservice modules.
- Improved the performance of mission-critical features by 25% by optimizing code and database queries.

Technology Analyst, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2018-2019

- Developed client's HR Portal which was a regulated product with highly sensitive data and numerical operations.
- Reduced the operational costs of the portal by 20% by re-writing Coldfusion application using Java & Spring Boot.
- · Improved the efficiency and security of the modules by 80% by re-architecting backend services for the cloud.

Associate Software Engineer, CGI Inc

India - 2016-2018

- Developed a framework to manage the state of system which reduced the maintenance downtime by 95%.
- Migrated SOAP web services to REST endpoints using modern Spring Boot-based microservices.

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate, Computer Application Security, Conestoga College	Waterloo, ON
Postgraduate Certificate, Cloud Computing & Blockchain, Saskatchewan Polytechnic	Saskatoon, SK
Master of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology	India
Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology	India

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Security+, CompTIA	Pursuing
AWS Certified Developer Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	Pursuing
AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	FPDELC1KXFF1QXK5
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	JJMV6422RJ1Q1NWV

SKILLS

Backend	Java, Microse	vices, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, JPA, Hibernate, REST, GraphQL, Git, SQL, OpenAPI, Swagger
Infra / Cloud	AWS (EC2, S3	3, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, IAM), GCP, GitHub Actions, Docker, Jenkins
Security	pfSense, GVIV	I, Nessus, Cryptography, PKI, Risk Assessment, Threat Modelling, Ghidra, IDA, Reconnaissance
Frontend	SSG, SSR, Ty	pescript, React, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Next.is, Astro.is

AWARDS

Conestoga	- High Distinction Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Computer Application Security.	2024
Conestoga	- Best of Program Award, Best Capstone Project in Computer Application Security program.	2024
Saskpoly	- Dean's List Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Cloud Computing & Blockchain.	2023
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Technical contribution to the success of the eCX project. 	2022
Deloitte	 Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the STAR Migration project. 	2020
Deloitte	 Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the HRAlly project. 	2019
Deloitte	- Applause Award, Project delivery excellence during the development of the HRAlly project.	2019
Deloitte	 Spot Award, Critical support during CSP 2.0 project go-live. 	2019
Deloitte	 Applause Award, Delivery excellence during CSP 2.0 project development. 	2018
CGI	 Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery, and individual contribution to the M2M GDSP project. 	2017

PROJECTS

Blog	_	Self-taught React, Typescript, TailwindCSS, Next.js, and Astro.js to build a blog with a simple design.
OSCAR	_	Secured Maven build supply chain for OSCAR, an open-source Canadian Healthcare EMR system.
Emoverse	_	Built a full-stack journaling platform using AWS serverless services, and fully automated CI-CD pipeline.
SmartDegree	_	Built a DApp to issue digital certificates using Solidity and Web3 and deployed on Ethereum blockchain.
DevMyMacX	_	Self-taught shell scripting to automate user and developer environment setup on a fresh macOS install.
DevMyLinuX	-	Self-taught shell scripting to automate Arch Linux OS and environment setup with minimal user interaction.

PUBLICATIONS

Research Paper

- + An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System.
- + Published in the IEEE Journal https://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRITO.2014.7014723